Guide to the Zebulon Alexander Terry Scrapbook
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Zebulon Alexander Terry scrapbook
1905-1982
1910-1917
SC0503
Terry, Zebulon Alexander.
2 Linear feet
This scrapbook primarily documents Terry's life as a student at Stanford and includes photographs, clippings, athletic event programs and tickets, theatrical programs, invitations, his class cards, dance cards, and other memorabilia. Subjects include athletics (football, baseball, track, and crew), the Delta Tau Delta fraternity, and student amusements such as the Frosh-Soph Tie-Up, Peerades, and the Plug Ugly. There are also clippings and photographs pertaining to Terry's professional athletic career and memorabilia from his tour in the armed services during World War I.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Zebulon Alexander Terry graduated from Stanford University in 1914 with an A.B. in economics. He was shortstop on the Stanford baseball team, serving as captain of the team in 1913 and 1914. After graduation, he played professional baseball with the Chicago White Sox, the Pittsburgh Pirates, and the Chicago Cubs.
Description of the Collection
This scrapbook primarily documents Terry's life as a student at Stanford and includes photographs, clippings, athletic event programs and tickets, theatrical programs, invitations, his class cards, dance cards, and other memorabilia. Subjects include athletics (football, baseball, track, and crew), the Delta Tau Delta fraternity, and student amusements such as the Frosh-Soph Tie-Up, Peerades, and the Plug Ugly. There are also clippings and photographs pertaining to Terry's professional athletic career and memorabilia from his tour in the armed services during World War I.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Terry, Zebulon Alexander.; Baseball players--United States.; Photoprints.; Scrapbooks
Collection Contents
- Scrapbook
  - Scrapbook pages pertaining to Stanford athletics, Delta Tau Delta fraternity, and student social life; also includes two photographs of Terry during professional ballgames (Box 1, Folder 1-9)
  - Scrapbook pages pertaining to student social life, Terry's professional baseball career, and his World War I military service (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
  - Scrapbook covers (Box 2)
  - Clipping, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Commencement items, 1943 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: letter from David Starr Jordan, 1913; telegram offering baseball position, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Daily Palo Alto issues, 1911-1914 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, loose, from scrapbook (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Photographs of Terry and other pro players, 1932-33 and undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Senior Week booklet, 1915 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stanford publications (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Track and field meet (Stanford and California), program, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 9)